Are ya ready, kids?
孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
[kids] Aye-aye, Captain!
[孩子们] 是啊，队长！
I can't hear you.
我听不到你说话。
[kids] Aye-aye, Captain!
[孩子们] 是啊，队长！
♪ Oh... ♪
♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
[kids] ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
[孩子们] ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
[Painty] ♪ Absorbent,
and yellow, and porous is he ♪
[油漆] ♪ 吸收性，
黄色、多孔的是他 ♪
[kids] ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
[孩子们] ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
[Painty] ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
[Painty] ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
[kids] ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
[孩子们] ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
[Painty] ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
[Painty] ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
-♪ SpongeBob SquarePants
-♪ Ready? ♪
-♪ 海绵宝宝
-♪ 准备好了吗？ ♪
[all] ♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
[全部] ♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
[Painty]
♪ SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
[油漆]
♪ 海绵宝宝 ♪
[Painty laughing]
[佩蒂笑]
-[flute playing]
-[song ends]
-[长笛演奏]
-[歌曲结束]
-[waves lapping]
-[gulls squawking]
-[海浪拍打]
-[海鸥嘎嘎叫]
[mysterious music playing]
【神秘音乐响起】
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
-[upbeat jazz music playing]
-[Squidward humming]
-[欢快的爵士乐演奏]
-[章鱼哥嗡嗡声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Perfect.
完美的。
Woo.
呜。
Evening, neighbor.
晚上好，邻居。
Evening, Preston.
晚上好，普雷斯顿。
[engine humming]
[发动机嗡嗡声]
Good luck
at the concert tonight.
祝你好运
今晚的音乐会上。
Thank you, Sebastian.
谢谢你，塞巴斯蒂安。
[Squidward, VO]
You may think you know me,
[章鱼哥，画外音]
你可能认为你了解我，
but you don't.
但你没有。
I used to be
Squidward Tentacles,
我曾经是
章鱼哥的触手，
but now, the name's...
但现在，这个名字是……
Dolphin, John Dolphin.
海豚，约翰·海豚。
[upbeat classical music playing]
【欢快的古典音乐演奏】
It's John Dolphin!
这是约翰·海豚！
[crowd clamoring excitedly]
[人群兴奋地叫嚷]
[crowd gasps]
[人群喘息]
[triangle chimes]
[三角铃]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
[Squidward, VO]
I have a wonderful new life
[章鱼哥，画外音]
我有美好的新生活
in New Kelp City.
在新海带城。
How did this happen?
这是怎么发生的？
Well, I'll tell you.
好吧，我告诉你。
One day, the worst thing
that ever happened to me
有一天，最糟糕的事情
这曾经发生在我身上
turned out to be
原来是
the best thing
that ever happened to me.
最好的事情
这曾经发生在我身上。
[door opens, closes]
[门打开，关闭]
Excuse me.
I'd like to lodge a complaint.
打扰一下。
我想投诉。
This reed is defective.
这根簧片有缺陷。
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
[playing out of tune]
[演奏走调]
[cracks, shatters]
[裂缝、破碎]
[boing]
[嗡嗡声]
[groans, coughs]
[呻吟，咳嗽]
I'm sorry, sir,
对不起，先生，
but that's the only reed
we have in stock.
但这是唯一的芦苇
我们有库存。
Have you ever thought
of playing something safer,
你有没有想过
玩一些更安全的东西，
like the triangle?
像三角形？
-[eraser squeaking]
-[glass shatters]
-[橡皮擦吱吱声]
-[玻璃碎裂]
-[rock music plays]
-This is a stickup.
-[摇滚音乐响起]
-这是一个粘贴。
Give me all the dough
in the joint,
把所有的面团都给我
在联合处，
or I'll rub you out.
不然我就把你擦掉。
[squeak]
[吱]
Elmer Eraser!
埃尔默橡皮擦！
[chuckles]
[笑声]
If either of you bozos squeal,
如果你们中的任何一个蠢货尖叫
I'll track ya down
我会追踪你
and rub you out.
并把你擦掉。
[rock music continues]
[摇滚乐继续]
I won't say a syllable.
我不会说一个音节。
See that you don't,
or Elmer Eraser will find you.
看看你没有，
或者埃尔默橡皮擦会找到你。
-[rock music ends]
-[indistinct chatter]
-[摇滚乐结束]
-[含糊不清的喋喋不休]
[Squidward, VO] The police tried
to get me to talk,
[章鱼哥，画外音] 警方尝试过
让我说话，
but I wasn't interested...
但我不感兴趣...
at first.
起初。
I told you,
I didn't see a thing.
我告诉过你，
我什么也没看到。
Not to worry, Mr. Tentacles.
别担心，触手先生。
If you do remember anything,
如果你还记得什么的话
we can put you
into witness protection.
我们可以把你
纳入证人保护。
Of course, we'll have
to move you to a new town,
当然，我们会有
把你搬到一个新的城镇，
change your name,
and give you a new job.
改变你的名字，
并给你一份新工作。
Look, officer, I'm not talking.
听着，警官，我不是在说话。
Unfortunately, you'll never see
your friends or neighbors again.
不幸的是，你永远不会看到
再次你的朋友或邻居。
I saw everything.
我看到了一切。
I'll testify.
我会作证。
[Squidward, VO]
Now, I have everything
[章鱼哥，画外音]
现在，我拥有了一切
-I'd ever dreamed of.
-[crowd cheering]
-我曾经梦想过。
-[人群欢呼]
[triangle chimes]
[三角铃]
[crowd cheering and applauding]
[人群欢呼鼓掌]
[Patrick giggling]
[帕特里克咯咯笑]
Huh?
啊？
[SpongeBob laughing]
[海绵宝宝大笑]
I must be imagining things.
我一定是在想象一些事情。
[crowd clamoring excitedly]
[人群兴奋地叫嚷]
Huh?!
啊？！
[SpongeBob and Patrick cheering]
[海绵宝宝和帕特里克欢呼]
This can't be happening!
[exclaims]
这不可能发生！
[惊呼]
-[thudding]
-[Squidward whimpers nervously]
-[重击]
-[章鱼哥紧张地呜咽]
[whimpers nervously]
[紧张地呜咽]
[together] We miss you,
Squidward.
[合]我们想念你
章鱼哥。
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
[tires screech]
[轮胎尖叫声]
[upbeat, comical music playing]
[播放欢快、滑稽的音乐]
[together] Hi, Squidward.
[合]嗨，章鱼哥。
-[crash]
-[tires screech]
-[崩溃]
-[轮胎尖叫声]
[Squidward panting]
[章鱼哥气喘吁吁]
-[crashing]
-[whimpering nervously]
-[崩溃]
-[紧张地呜咽]
-[screech to a halt]
-[whimpers nervously]
-[尖叫着停了下来]
-[紧张地呜咽]
[SpongeBob] Don't worry.
I've got it.
[海绵宝宝] 别担心。
我明白了。
Love your new beard.
喜欢你的新胡子。
Thanks, but it's only
a fake one. Huh?
谢谢，但这只是
一个假的。啊？
SpongeBob and Patrick?!
海绵宝宝和帕特里克？！
How did you two goofballs
find me?
你们两个混蛋怎么了
找到我吗？
[SpongeBob, VO]
Oh, you like to know
[海绵宝宝，画外音]
哦，你想知道吗
how we found you, Squidward?
我们是怎么找到你的，章鱼哥？
Um, eh...
Where's your voice coming from?
嗯，呃...
你的声音从哪里来？
[SpongeBob]
It was an average day
[海绵宝宝]
这是平凡的一天
at the old Krusty Krab.
在老蟹堡。
-But something was missing.
-[customers murmuring]
-但是缺少了一些东西。
-[顾客窃窃私语]
Or should I say "someone"?
或者我应该说“某人”？
Hello?
你好？
-Anybody home?
-[thud]
-有人在家吗？
-[砰]
Boy, the service here
兄弟，这里的服务
is really going downhill,
SpongeBob.
真的是在走下坡路
海绵宝宝。
Squidward's still not here?
I guess that would explain
章鱼哥还没来吗？
我想这可以解释
why I haven't had a single order
in weeks.
为什么我没有一个订单
几周后。
I haven't seen him in his house
for weeks either,
我没在他家里见过他
也有几周的时间，
not even in his bathtub.
甚至在他的浴缸里也不行。
And his fridge is out of food!
而且他的冰箱里没有食物了！
I really miss
my favorite neighbor.
我真的很想念
我最喜欢的邻居。
But I'm right here, buddy.
但我就在这里，伙计。
Oh, thank goodness.
哦，谢天谢地。
But how do we find Squidward?
但我们如何找到章鱼哥呢？
Don't worry. I got this.
不用担心。我明白了。
[stretch, pop]
[拉伸、弹出]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
Now, I just need something
that smells like Squidward.
现在，我只需要一些东西
闻起来像章鱼哥。
One of his old clarinet reeds
should help.
他的一根旧单簧管簧片
应该有帮助。
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
Ew!
呃！
[sniffing, barking] Got it!
[嗅嗅，吠叫]明白了！
[panting, barking]
[气喘吁吁，吠叫]
-[bowling pins clatter]
-[people groan]
-[保龄球瓶碰撞声]
-[人们呻吟]
And so, we followed the scent
to your new front door.
于是我们循着气味
到你的新前门。
Why did you leave us, Squidward?
你为什么离开我们，章鱼哥？
[grumbles] You knuckleheads
are gonna ruin everything.
[抱怨]你们这些笨蛋
会毁了一切。
I'm in witness protection.
我正在接受证人保护。
Fitness infection?
健身感染？
I'm hiding out
from Elmer Eraser.
我躲起来了
来自埃尔默橡皮擦。
Elmer Eraser?!
埃尔默橡皮擦？！
The robber who relishes
in rubbing out rats?
喜欢的强盗
消灭老鼠？
-[Squidward grunts]
-[exclaiming]
-[章鱼哥咕哝]
-[惊呼]
Would you two get lost?
你们两个会迷路吗？
You're gonna lead that maniac
right to me.
你会带领那个疯子
对我来说是对的。
[door slams]
[关门声]
-Gee!
-[squeaks]
-哎呀！
-[吱吱声]
I had no idea Squidward was
in witless perfection.
我不知道章鱼哥是
在无知的完美中。
And we almost blew his cover.
我们差点就暴露了他的身份。
[feet screech]
[脚尖叫]
Hey, sorry about that.
嘿，对此感到抱歉。
I didn't see ya there.
我在那儿没看到你。
Say, that sure is a nice eraser.
说吧，这确实是一块很好的橡皮擦。
Thanks. My mommy made it for me.
谢谢。我妈妈给我做的。
Hmm. Eraser.
唔。橡皮。
That reminds me of something,
but what?
这让我想起一件事
但什么？
Do you bozos know
where I can find...
你们笨蛋知道吗
我在哪里可以找到...
this mug?
这个杯子？
[gasps]
[喘气]
Elmer Eraser?
埃尔默橡皮擦？
Oh, that's not a mug. That's--
哦，那不是杯子。那是——
We've never seen that person
in our entire lives...
我们从未见过那个人
在我们的一生中...
uh, with or without a beard.
呃，有或没有胡子。
Well, if you do...
好吧，如果你这样做...
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
...please let me know.
...请告诉我。
Patrick, that was Elmer Eraser.
帕特里克，那是埃尔默橡皮擦。
Who?
WHO？
We gotta warn Squidward.
我们得警告章鱼哥。
Phew! Thank Neptune
those idiots are gone.
唷！评分此翻译： 感谢你的评分 不好 好
那些白痴已经走了。
[together] Squidward!
[合]章鱼哥！
[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣声]
And they're back.
他们回来了。
Guess who we saw outside?
猜猜我们在外面看到了谁？
Elmer Eraser!
埃尔默橡皮擦！
What?!
什么？！
Oh, I'm doomed!
哦，我注定了！
Don't worry. We'll put you into
witness protection protection.
不用担心。我们会把你放入
证人保护保护。
You're safe with us.
和我们在一起你很安全。
-Whoa!
-[glass shatters]
-哇！
-[玻璃碎裂]
Here's a hideout
with a lot of natural light.
这里是一个藏身处
拥有充足的自然光。
-[thud]
-[Squidward grunts]
-[砰]
-[章鱼哥咕哝]
-[upbeat music playing]
-[door slams]
-[欢快的音乐播放]
-[关门声]
A glass house? Are you nuts?
玻璃房子？你疯了吗？
This way, you can see
Elmer Eraser coming.
这样你就可以看到
埃尔默橡皮擦来了。
But he can see me too.
但他也能看到我。
You!
你！
You guys lied to me.
你们对我撒谎了。
That's Squidward!
那是章鱼哥！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Don't worry. I got him.
不用担心。我抓住了他。
-Wait! Don't!
-[grunts]
-等待！不！
-[咕哝]
-[thump]
-[crumbling]
-[重击]
-[崩溃]
Oh!
哦！
It's a plexiglass house.
这是一座有机玻璃房子。
[both panting anxiously]
[两人都焦急地喘着气]
[clinking]
[叮叮当当]
Perfect!
完美的！
We can drive far, far away.
我们可以开车去很远很远的地方。
[engine starts, revs]
[发动机启动，转速]
[clanking]
[叮当声]
Gotcha!
明白了！
Everybody jump!
大家跳起来吧！
[all grunt]
[全都咕哝]
This is how you make a getaway.
这就是你逃跑的方式。
-[engine revs]
-Wait.
-[发动机转速]
-等等。
-[all screaming]
-[thud]
-[全都尖叫]
-[砰]
[comical music plays]
[滑稽的音乐响起]
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
Quick! In there!
快的！在那里！
[upbeat music plays]
[欢快的音乐响起]
[thud, pop]
[砰砰声，砰砰声]
[thudding]
[重击]
[eraser squeaking]
[橡皮擦的吱吱声]
[all whimpering]
[全都呜咽]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
Up there!
上面！
[all grunting]
[全都咕哝]
[grumbles, grunts]
[抱怨声，咕哝声]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
[thud]
[砰]
[upbeat music continues]
[欢快的音乐继续]
[door closes]
[门关上]
[SpongeBob] You'll be safe
in here.
[海绵宝宝] 你会安全的
在这里。
[growling]
[咆哮]
Gotcha!
明白了！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
-[door slams open]
-[grunts]
-[门猛地打开]
-[咕哝]
Squidward is unprotected.
章鱼哥没有受到保护。
Hop on!
跳上来！
[upbeat music continues]
[欢快的音乐继续]
-[horn honks]
-Huh?
-[喇叭鸣响]
-啊？
[together] We'll save you,
Squidward!
[一起]我们会拯救你，
章鱼哥！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Oh, no!
哦，不！
Those two halfwits found me.
那两个笨蛋找到了我。
[laughs]
[笑]
Phew! It's just Elmer Eraser.
唷！这只是埃尔默橡皮擦。
Elmer Eraser!
埃尔默橡皮擦！
[SpongeBob and Patrick
screaming]
[海绵宝宝和帕特里克
尖叫]
We'll protect you, Squidward.
我们会保护你，章鱼哥。
-[Elmer Eraser] Gotcha!
-[exclaims]
-[埃尔默橡皮擦]明白了！
-[惊呼]
Please, Elmer Eraser,
don't rub out Squidward.
拜托，埃尔默橡皮擦，
别抹掉章鱼哥。
Aw, don't worry.
噢，别担心。
I'm not Elmer.
我不是埃尔默。
I'm Detective Eraser.
我是橡皮侦探。
[whimpers woozily]
[迷迷糊糊地呜咽]
Elmer's my twin brother.
埃尔默是我的双胞胎兄弟。
I've been trying to find you
all day.
我一直在努力寻找你
一整天。
Oh, thank goodness.
哦，谢天谢地。
Can you arrest
these two blockheads
你能逮捕吗
这两个笨蛋
so I can go back
to being John Dolphin?
这样我就可以回去
成为约翰·海豚？
Lucky for you, my brother Elmer
has been caught and put in jail.
你很幸运，我的兄弟埃尔默
已被抓获并投入监狱。
You don't need
witness protection anymore.
你不需要
不再有证人保护了。
[Squidward grunting]
[章鱼哥咕哝]
Ouch.
哎哟。
Isn't it great, Squidward?
不是很棒吗，章鱼哥？
You can come back
to Bikini Bottom with us.
你可以回来
和我们一起去比基尼泳裤。
-Squidward's back!
-Yay!
-章鱼哥回来了！
-耶！
-Wonderful.
-Squidward's back!
-精彩的。
-章鱼哥回来了！
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[jaunty music playing]
[欢快的音乐]
-You're it.
-No, you're it.
-就是你了。
-不，你就是了。
No, you're it.
不，你就是了。
-Squidward's it.
-No, you're it.
-章鱼哥就是它。
-不，你就是了。
[Squidward, VO]
I was finally safe,
[章鱼哥，画外音]
我终于安全了
but I was about to become
witness to another crime,
但我即将成为
目睹另一起犯罪行为，
a crime I was going to commit.
我即将犯下的罪行。
I'm going to rub you out!
我要把你擦掉！
[both scream]
[两人尖叫]
[laughing maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
Rub. Rub. Rub.
擦。擦。擦。
[laughing maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
[surf rock music playing]
[冲浪摇滚音乐播放]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[bluegrass music playing]
[蓝草音乐演奏]
Boy, that was one heck
of a shoppin' spree
男孩，那真是太糟糕了
疯狂购物
down at the old Nut Barn.
在老坚果谷仓。
[sucking]
[吸吮]
Ah.
啊。
[crunches, gulps]
Worth it, though.
[仰卧起坐，吞咽]
不过还是值得的。
[crunching]
[嘎吱嘎吱]
These cracklin' nuts
taste so good,
这些坚果
味道真好，
it's like there's a hootenanny
in my mouth.
就好像有一个胡特纳尼
在我嘴里。
Bleh!
哎呀！
Yeehaw!
耶哈！
-[crunching]
-[acorns screaming]
-[嘎吱嘎吱]
-[橡子尖叫]
-[thud]
-[grunts]
-[砰]
-[咕哝]
[groaning]
Where'd that come fr--
[呻吟]
那是从哪里来的——
-[gasps]
-[cracking]
-[喘气]
-[破裂]
Oh, my helmet's about to crack
like an egg.
哦，我的头盔快要裂了
像鸡蛋一样。
I gotta get home
to my dome ASAP.
我得回家了
尽快到我的圆顶。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
-[grunts]
-[glass shatters]
-[咕哝]
-[玻璃碎裂]
[gasping]
[喘气]
That was a close shave.
那是一次险胜。
Better dig out my backup helmet.
最好把我的备用头盔挖出来。
[whirring]
[呼呼]
Aha!
啊哈！
[shattering]
[破碎]
Whoops! Must be
all that nut dust on my fingers.
哎呀！必须是
我手指上沾满了坚果粉。
Looks like I'm plumb out
of helmets.
看起来我已经铅垂了
的头盔。
Better order a new one.
最好订购一件新的。
[upbeat music playing]
[欢快的音乐播放]
-[dialing]
-[line connects]
-[拨号]
-[线路连接]
Hello? Helmets Direct?
你好？直接戴头盔？
Yeah, I need another one.
是的，我需要另一份。
-[man] What size do you need?
-Size? Size? Squirrel medium.
-[男士]您需要什么尺寸？
-尺寸？尺寸？松鼠中等。
-We're out of size medium.
-Uh-huh.
- 我们的中号尺码不够了。
-呃哈。
-I'll have to special order it.
-Uh-huh.
-我必须特别订购。
-呃哈。
It's gonna take six
to eight weeks to get it.
需要六个
八周才能得到它。
Six to eight weeks?
六到八周？
[sighs] Looks like
I'm stuck inside for a while.
[叹气]看起来像
我被困在里面一段时间了。
But I got plenty to do.
但我还有很多事要做。
[upbeat country music playing]
[欢快的乡村音乐演奏]
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
[blows landing]
[吹着陆]
-[grunting]
-[keyboard clacking]
-[咕哝]
-[键盘咔哒声]
[timer dings]
[计时器的声音]
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
[chittering]
[叽叽喳喳]
[music continues]
[音乐继续]
[chirping]
[叽叽喳喳]
[music slows, distorts]
[音乐变慢、扭曲]
[off-key notes]
[走调笔记]
[music slows and distorts]
[音乐变慢并扭曲]
-[music ends]
-[thud]
-[音乐结束]
-[砰]
It's only been one hour,
才过了一个小时，
but I can't take it anymore.
但我再也受不了了。
If I don't see
another living critter soon,
如果我没有看到
很快又一个活生生的动物，
I'm gonna go nuts.
我要发疯了。
-Nuts. [chuckles]
-[rim shot]
-坚果。 [笑声]
-[边缘射击]
[acorn] Hey, now, Sandy.
[橡子]嘿，现在，桑迪。
You'd never go nuts.
你永远不会发疯。
Your grip on reality
is too firm.
你对现实的把握
太坚定了。
Thanks, Nutty Buddy.
谢谢，坚果好友。
You're always here for me.
你总是在我身边。
[Nutty Buddy] That's what
friends are for.
[臭小子] 就是这样
朋友是为了。
Maybe I can lasso someone
into coming over.
也许我可以套住某人
过来。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
-[busy signal beeping]
-[French Narrator reading]
-[忙音提示音]
-[法语旁白朗读]
I don't understand.
我不明白。
How can everyone be busy
at 2:30 on a Tuesday?
怎么大家都忙起来
周二 2:30？
Oh, I know!
哦，我知道！
If I can't get my friends
to visit me,
如果我联系不到我的朋友
来拜访我，
I'll visit them...
我去拜访他们...
remotely.
远程。
-[whirring]
-[adventurous music playing]
-[呼呼]
-[冒险音乐播放]
-[whirring]
-[adventurous music continues]
-[呼呼]
-[冒险音乐继续]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[sighs] You got this.
[叹气]你明白了。
[whimpering nervously]
You got it.
[紧张地呜咽]
你明白了。
Well, that's about as exciting
as riding a no-legged bull.
嗯，这同样令人兴奋
就像骑一头无腿的公牛一样。
Next!
下一个！
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[exclaiming]
[惊呼]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
Very good.
非常好。
Now, let's try parallel parking.
现在，让我们尝试平行停车。
[yawns]
[哈欠]
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
[surf rock music playing]
[冲浪摇滚音乐播放]
-And... done.
-[ding]
-然后...完成了。
-[叮]
Now, for 10,000 with this arm.
现在，用这只手臂换一万个。
-One... [grunts]
-[ding]
-一个...[咕哝]
-[叮]
Two...
二...
-[ding]
-[grunts]
-[叮]
-[咕哝]
-Three...
-[Sandy snoring]
-三...
-[桑迪打鼾]
[grunts] This is making
my eyelids feel heavier
[咕噜声]这是在做
我的眼皮感觉更重
than Larry's weights.
比拉里的体重。
Next!
下一个！
-[grunting]
-[bonk]
-[咕哝]
-[棒棒哒]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
-[flying camera whirring]
-[upbeat music playing]
-[飞行相机呼呼]
-[欢快的音乐播放]
-And done.
-[cash register dings]
-完成了。
-[收银机叮叮声]
Phew! Now for 10,000
with this arm.
唷！现在10,000
用这只手臂。
-One...
-[cash register dings]
-一个...
-[收银机叮叮声]
-Two...
-[cash register dings]
-两个...
-[收银机叮叮声]
-Three...
-[cash register dings]
-三...
-[收银机叮叮声]
[Sandy grumbles]
[桑迪抱怨]
[Mr. Krabs] Four...
[先生。蟹]四...
Yeesh! Gah!
是啊！嘎！
Five...
五...
[gasps]
[喘气]
[Sandy] There's gotta be
something interesting
[桑迪] 一定有
一些有趣的事情
-to look at in this town.
-[thud]
-在这个小镇上看看。
-[砰]
-[static crackles]
-Huh?
-[静态爆裂声]
-啊？
What in the...?
什么在...？
Of course!
当然！
That big old metal whatsit
I ran into.
那个又大又旧的金属是什么东西
我碰到了。
Plankton?
浮游生物？
Better go in for a closer look.
最好进去仔细看看。
-[Plankton whistling]
-[whirring]
-[浮游生物的呼啸声]
-[呼呼]
Huh? What's that noise?
啊？那是什么声音？
[sighs] Did I leave Karen on
all night again?
[叹气]我有没有留下凯伦
又整夜了？
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[whirring rapidly]
[快速呼呼]
Whoa. Mosquitos sure are
getting big this year.
哇哦。蚊子肯定有
今年变大了。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
[whirring, clanking]
[呼呼声、叮当声]
Dang that Plankton!
该死的浮游生物！
Now I gottafigure out
what he's up to.
现在我得弄清楚
他在做什么。
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
-[phone ringing]
-[SpongeBob] Yello?
-[电话铃声]
-[海绵宝宝] 你好？
Heya, SpongeBob.
嘿，海绵宝宝。
I'm in the middle
of an investigation,
我在中间
的一项调查，
and I was hoping you could do
a little reconnoitering for me.
我希望你能做到
对我来说有点侦察。
-[blade swishes]
-Hyah! Gosh, Sandy, I'd love to,
-[刀锋嗖嗖]
-哈！天哪，桑迪，我很乐意，
but I'm already reconnoitering
a new mustard mine
但我已经在侦察了
一个新的芥末矿
for Mr. Krabs.
给蟹老板的。
[sinister growling]
[险恶的咆哮]
-[growling, shrieking]
-[screaming]
-[咆哮，尖叫]
-[尖叫]
-[gorilla grunting]
-[SpongeBob screaming]
-[大猩猩咕哝]
-[海绵宝宝尖叫]
I get it. I get it. You're busy.
我得到它。我得到它。你很忙。
You don't have to holler
about it.
你不必大喊大叫
关于它。
[dialing]
[拨号]
-[phone ringing]
-Uh...
-[电话铃声]
-呃...
-[ringing continues]
-Huh?
-[铃声继续]
-啊？
-Hello?
-[Sandy] Howdy, Patrick.
-你好？
-[桑迪]你好，帕特里克。
I'm trying to peep
Plankton's plans.
我正试图偷看
浮游生物的计划。
Wanna help out?
想帮忙吗？
Sure. I'll be over
当然。我会结束的
as soon as I finish my sandwich.
我一吃完三明治。
Okay. [murmurs]
好的。 [低语]
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
[bubbling]
[冒泡]
All right, Patrick.
This should be simple enough.
好吧，帕特里克。
这应该很简单。
Plankton is building
some sort of evil device.
浮游生物正在建造
某种邪恶的装置。
All you gotta do is head
over there with my camera
你所要做的就是头
带着我的相机在那边
and give it a look 'fer. Roger?
并看看它。罗杰？
A look 'fer. Roger!
一看。罗杰！
[adventurous music playing]
[冒险的音乐演奏]
[low whirring]
[低呼呼声]
[Sandy] Whatcha...
[桑迪] 啥……
doin' there, Patrick?
帕特里克，在那儿做什么？
Looking for Roger.
寻找罗杰.
[Sandy sighs] Let me give you
a little help.
[桑迪叹气]让我给你
一点帮助。
[exclaiming, spluttering]
[惊呼，溅水]
[thud]
[砰]
Karen, I'm going out
for coffee and crullers.
凯伦，我要出去
咖啡和油条。
[Sandy] Perfect! Snoop around
while Plankton's gone.
[桑迪] 完美！窥探周围
当浮游生物消失时。
Oh, boy! I love snooping.
哦，孩子！我喜欢窥探。
♪ Snoop, snoop, snooper snoop,
snoopy snoop ♪
♪ 窥探，窥探，窥探，窥探，
史努比史努比♪
Keep your eyes peeled for a clue
睁大眼睛寻找线索
that might tell us
what he's up to.
这可能会告诉我们
他在做什么。
Blueprints, memory cards,
microfiche...
蓝图、存储卡、
缩微胶片...
[Patrick]
Ooh, I found something!
[帕特里克]
哦，我发现了一些东西！
-Is it a clue?
-Yeah!
-这是一个线索吗？
-是的！
A delicious one.
美味的一个。
It's his lunch.
这是他的午餐。
[Patrick giggles]
[帕特里克咯咯笑]
[munching] Mmm!
[咀嚼]嗯！
Patrick, that ain't a clue.
That's a tiny burrito.
帕特里克，这不是线索。
这是一个小墨西哥卷饼。
[Patrick] Okay, okay.
[帕特里克] 好吧，好吧。
[burrito whistles through air]
[墨西哥卷饼在空中吹口哨]
[Patrick munches, gulps]
[帕特里克咀嚼，吞咽]
Here, Roger, Roger.
在这里，罗杰，罗杰。
Ugh, there's nothing here.
呃，这里什么都没有。
Just this dumb old box of...
只是这个愚蠢的旧盒子......
"puh-loo-toe-ni-um!" Who cares?
“噗-卢-托-尼-嗯！”谁在乎？
Plutonium?! [exclaims]
钚？！ [惊呼]
Plankton must be building
some sort of atomic weapon!
浮游生物一定正在建造
某种原子武器！
[gasping] And it's pointed
right at the Krusty Krab!
[喘气]而且它是尖的
就在蟹堡王那里！
All right, Patrick,
you've done your part.
好吧，帕特里克，
你已经尽了你的职责。
These glow sticks
make my bones itchy.
这些荧光棒
让我的骨头发痒。
Now I'm gonna zap him
with my laser.
现在我要消灭他
用我的激光。
-She's warming up now.
-[laser beeping]
-她现在正在热身。
-[激光蜂鸣声]
[Plankton]
♪ Do, do, do, dee... ♪
[浮游生物]
♪ 做，做，做，迪……♪
[Sandy] Oh, no! Plankton's back.
[桑迪]哦，不！浮游生物回来了。
Patrick, you gotta get
outta there.
帕特里克，你必须得到
离开那里。
-Don't let him see you!
-[munching]
-别让他看到你！
-[咀嚼]
-Hurry!
-Huh.
-匆忙！
-嗯。
I am like unto the wind.
我就像风一样。
[Japanese string music plays]
[日本弦乐演奏]
Whoa! [gasping]
哇！ [喘气]
Hey! [gasping] Whoa!
嘿！ [喘气]哇！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[comedic musical sting]
[喜剧音乐刺]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
What are you doing here, bozo?
你在这里做什么，博佐？
My name's Patrick,
我叫帕特里克
not Bozo.
不是博佐。
Yeah, no duh, Sherlock.
是的，不，夏洛克。
My name's Bozo, not Sherlock.
我的名字是博佐，不是夏洛克。
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
Oh, no! He's onto us.
哦，不！他来找我们了。
Time to take out that weapon.
[grunts]
是时候拿出那件武器了。
[咕哝]
[laser humming]
[激光嗡嗡声]
I know your name, ding dong!
我知道你的名字，叮咚！
My name's Sherlock,
not Ding Dong.
我的名字是夏洛克
不是丁东。
Enough! It doesn't matter.
足够的！没关系。
You're gonna be the first
你将成为第一个
to witness
my latest evil invention.
见证
我最新的邪恶发明。
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[rattling]
[嘎嘎声]
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[upbeat music playing]
[欢快的音乐播放]
"Eat at the Chum Bucket."
“在 Chum Bucket 吃。”
It's just a dumb, old sign?
这只是一个愚蠢的、古老的标志吗？
That's not evil.
那不是邪恶的。
Well, the plutonium
wasn't sourced ethically,
嗯，钚
来源不符合道德规范，
so it's a little evil.
所以有点邪恶。
-[laser buzzing]
-[dramatic music playing]
-[激光嗡嗡声]
-[戏剧性音乐播放]
[creaking]
[吱吱作响]
Oh... boy.
哦...男孩。
[creaking]
[吱吱作响]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[surf rock music playing]
[冲浪摇滚音乐播放]
Huh?
啊？
Why didn't I think of that?
为什么我没有想到这一点？
Eat that, Krabs!
吃那个吧，蟹蟹们！
[laughs] Whoo!
[笑] 哇！
-[surf rock music plays]
-[French Narrator reading]
-[冲浪摇滚音乐响起]
-[法语旁白朗读]
Thanks for hosting me restaurant
谢谢你招待我的餐厅
while the Krusty Krab
is being repaired...
而蟹堡王
正在修复中...
and while SpongeBob's recovering
from his gorilla injuries.
当海绵宝宝康复时
从他的大猩猩受伤中。
It's the least I could do.
这是我至少能做的。
-[doorbell rings]
-Huh?
-[门铃响了]
-啊？
My helmet! Finally!
我的头盔！最后！
[helmet shattering]
[头盔碎裂]
Me new restaurant! Finally!
我的新餐厅！最后！
Quit yer loafin', Mr. Squidward.
别再游手好闲了，章鱼哥先生。
Ya got a buildin' to move.
你有一栋大楼要搬。
[squelching]
[压抑]
[sighs] Six to eight more weeks
on the inside?
[叹气]还有六到八周
在里面？
[laughs]
[笑]
[unhinged laughter]
[失控的笑声]
How-how about you take
the next shift, Nutty Buddy?
怎么样，你拿怎么样
下一个班次，疯子巴迪？
[unhinged laughter]
[失控的笑声]
[Nutty Buddy] Man, I gotta make
some new friends.
[坚果好友] 伙计，我得做
一些新朋友。
[closing theme playing]
【结束主题曲播放】